<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tim Whitacre</title>
    <description>Code. Music. Life.</description>    
    <link>http://timw.co</link>
    <atom:link href="http://timw.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Something Crazy</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to challenge you to do something crazy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the first line in an email I received less than 1 month after the startup I was at ran into some trouble. And crazy it is, but also very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Steph and I are moving to Atlanta.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to become a part of such an amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://theironyard.com/about/team/&quot;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; but also for all of the opportunity that Atlanta brings for both of us. I might write more about this in the months to come, but for now just read &lt;a href=&quot;http://stephwhitacre.com/chasing-dream/&quot;&gt;Steph&amp;#39;s post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I just want to publicly thank all of our friends and family who have been so incredibly helpful this last week. We could not do this without you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/05/13/something-crazy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/05/13/something-crazy.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Year for Whisk(e)y</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/timwco&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/timwco&quot;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; you know that I like to indulge once in a while. So far my drink of choice has been gin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/jkzy3AJG50/&quot;&gt;Plymouth Gin&lt;/a&gt; to be exact. As great as gin is, I have been told I should be drinking whiskey, at least some of the time. This includes all forms, bourbon, scotch, irish, rye and the likes. I’ll be honest, so far my favorite is rye with scotch being a close second but I have a long list to try and will hopefully be adding to the list as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even my wife is pushing me towards it by getting me the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Drink-More-Whiskey-Everything-Favorite/dp/1452109745&quot;&gt;Drink More Whiskey&lt;/a&gt; as well as some nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://buck4men.bigcartel.com/product/buck-signature-low-ball-glass&quot;&gt;low ball glasses&lt;/a&gt;, whiskey stones and everything else one might need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So without further ado, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/whiskey&quot;&gt;my whiskey list&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to hear your feedback. Is there something obvious I’ve missed or a small craft distillery I’ve not heard of? If you have any suggestions, hit me up on twitter as I’d love to see what else is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/04/01/the-year-for-whiskey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/04/01/the-year-for-whiskey.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So Many Bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t have to tell you this, but there is a lot of stuff on the internet. Obviously most of it is junk, but there is a lot of great content. This begs the question, “how do I consume it all” or rather, “how do I consume as much as I can that is relevant to me so I can keep up to speed in my industry”. This is not an easy task and because content and the way content is presented continually changes, you almost have no choice but to use some sort of service to help you keep up with it all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it is an aggregation service like &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenews.im/&quot;&gt;thenews.im&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyosity.com/interesting/&quot;&gt;interesting app&lt;/a&gt;, whatever your poison it still doesn’t help with things your friends, co-workers and twitter users share. You need a way to trap that content so when you have a chance to take a break you haven’t forgotten it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In walks &lt;a href=&quot;https://unmark.it&quot;&gt;Unmark&lt;/a&gt;. Many may have guessed I would talk about this eventually as I had a hand in building it, but I was part of this build because I knew the way I was saving my bookmarks was broken. Every service I used, while many were good, they still missed something. I’ve found that they just fill up with links I never visit again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this situation for example: I’m sitting at my desk working and a co-worker says I should read this article. I don’t want to stop what I’m doing but is throwing it into one of these services the best idea. I’m not even sure what the article is about and not sure if I really am interested in it. This is the same for videos, code examples and any other link that is shared or I stumble upon throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, IMO is why Unmark is so awesome. Our tagline for it is ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://unmark.it&quot;&gt;The to do app for your bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;”. This means as a piece of content comes along during the day, I can simply throw it into my Unmark account. Later that night from my iPad or phone I can go through the list of marks I saved and see if they really are as good as I first thought. If they are, I can send them to be read later, or watch the video right inside of Unmark. If it is a recipe, I can look at the ingredient list and determine if I want to put in in a recipe storage app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Unmark can be used in many different ways, this is how I use it and I have found it has changed the way I view content and the content I do end up consuming is more relevant and meaningful to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/03/28/so-many-bookmarks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/03/28/so-many-bookmarks.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scranton… Meet CoalWork</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coworking is not a new concept at all. In fact not too long ago while working from home I was doing a ton of research for a coworking spot in this area. Unfortunately there wasn’t one… or at least one that I could be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, anyone reading this who isn’t local might not realize that Scranton (and the surrounding area) is not a very technical place. I would even say that there are not really many tech companies in the area either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/PBs0tS46TlyZlmOGw7vl&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, some of the guys I work with are trying to change that. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://coalwork.com&quot;&gt;CoalWork&lt;/a&gt;, a forthcoming coworking spot. We are still in the early stages but hope this will become a staple in city. We hope through this we’ll meet some awesome people, learn some new things and possibly even change the way this area views tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is interested, feel free to check out the website or follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/coalwork&quot;&gt;CoalWork on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/02/25/scranton%E2%80%A6-meet-coalwork.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/02/25/scranton%E2%80%A6-meet-coalwork.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current Loves : iOS Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s finally starting to warm up here in Northeast PA and I’m neck deep in finishing a soon to be released update to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unmarkit&quot;&gt;Unmark&lt;/a&gt; (formerly nilai.co).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get asked quite often by friends what are the most used apps on my iPhone. I thought this would be a great place to share them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image below is a screenshot of my actual home screen on my iPhone 5. I’ve had it this way for probably the last 6 months and don’t plan to change anytime soon. Although with the thousands of app developers out there… that could change tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a breakdown of some of my favorite apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/6EeMF8uORle55vGcbtrr&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo App - &lt;a href=&quot;http://campl.us/&quot;&gt;Camera Plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/mobile/ios.html&quot;&gt;Chrome for iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather - &lt;a href=&quot;http://checktheweather.co/&quot;&gt;Check the Weather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anylistapp.com/&quot;&gt;AnyList&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reader - &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/ios/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pod Catcher - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shiftyjelly.com/pocketcasts&quot;&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music - &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/rdio/id335060889&quot;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News - &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyosity.com/interesting/&quot;&gt;Interesting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail - Default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar - Default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also do keep up on some social sites like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and Foursquare and thus they landed a spot on my home screen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also many others I didn’t mention. If you have any questions or wonder what any are, feel free to hit me up on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timwco&quot;&gt;tweetbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/02/20/current-loves-ios-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/02/20/current-loves-ios-edition.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on Email</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First, let me clarify my relationship with email. When it comes the jobs I’ve had, I went from working in an office, to working from home, doing freelance and now back in an office. It might not sound like much of a switch, but each one required different levels of communication to stay up to speed. For instance, my first office job was in a building that had about 150 employees. Not huge, but a lot of people were not close by. When it came to the developers and designers I was currently sharing a project with, we used instant message, but when it came to people in a different division (or people I’d rather not talk to that often) email came in mighty handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I left my first office job, and started working from home I realized that I would need to step up my email game. Again, anyone I was working with very closely, we kept in contact through IM or a chatroom like Campfire. The difference this time was not the size of the company (only about 10 people) but rather the fact that sometimes something was just too long to say in a quick message. At my office job, I would walk over to that person, pull up a chair and have a conversation. From home, this wasn’t possible. My options were either Skype or email. Since Skype takes a minimum of 10 minutes and 5 crashes before successfully starting, I usually chose email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today. I’m back working full time in an office. This time however, the team is small at only 7 people, with 5 of them being in earshot of me all day long. More important than this though, we’ve started using a program called &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; (which I highly recommend) and it has all but rid my need of email for the work I’m currently doing. We also use other tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; and Google Docs. All of this combined there isn’t much reason for me to open email at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on my current situation, I am going to try something. This has been suggested many times before by other people in a variety of ways, but starting today, I’m only going to check my email 3 times a day. I’m going to attempt to check it morning, noon and afternoon/evening. This way, I can still get back to people in a timely fashion but the constant barrage or email flooding in throughout the day won’t distract me from what I’m currently trying to accomplish. The only time I will break this is if someone needs something and I have to send it via email or if someone specifically tells me to check my email for an attachment. Otherwise, they will have to wait to get a response from me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, my biggest issue is not email from friends, family or co-workers, but rather the fringe email that makes its way in. I’ve signed up for quite a few newsletters over the years. Many I’m still happy to be a part of and a few that I wish would just let me unsubscribe. The problem isn’t that I don’t want to read them, but rather that I do. I want to see the updates on the new app coming out, and I want to read what some of my friends wrote about, but I don’t NEED to read about it right now. I’ve begun treating email like a glorified checklist of items I need to work through, with the goal of having all accomplished (archived or deleted). This means if one comes in while I’m working on something, the tendency is to jump over and take care of it. By removing the constant thread of email coming in throughout the day and limiting it to a few times a day, I can easily stay focused and possibly even reduce some stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always hit me up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timwco&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, as I’ll usually respond much quicker there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/02/10/thoughts-on-email.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/02/10/thoughts-on-email.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Year In Review : 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time of year, there are thousands of articles (likely more) being written with a similar title or one relating to next years resolutions. I know they are cliched and most people don&amp;#39;t really care all that much, but I did write an article at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.getbarley.com/2790/doing-more&quot;&gt;the beginning of this year&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to put out a recap of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article I&amp;#39;m referring to is titled &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.getbarley.com/2790/doing-more&quot;&gt;Doing More&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; and it was this idea that over the course of 2013 and all years following I would simply put a focus on doing bigger and better things each year. I also outlined quite a few goals such as loosing weight, reading more and doing things that I&amp;#39;ve always wanted. Unfortunately, I didn&amp;#39;t loose as much as I wanted this year, so that is one that I need to continue to work on. I did read more... a lot more actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did in 2013 that I have always wanted to do was going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/ZD00alJGw9&quot;&gt;Yosemite&lt;/a&gt;. Let me first say if you haven&amp;#39;t been there, start planning a trip right now, it is worth every penny. When I wrote that article, I had no idea that I would have the opportunity to go. Shortly into the month of January I realized that my wife and I had not been on a vacation (just the two of us) since our honeymoon 6+ years prior. I knew I needed to plan something but never thought it would have been to go across the country to one of the most beautiful places on earth. In short, it was life changing and I would go back every year (or week) if I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the biggest thing that happened to me this year was I officially jumped ship from the services industry to the product industry. I left my comfortable job of developing websites and apps for other people and joined an &lt;a href=&quot;http://plainmade.com/&quot;&gt;awesome team&lt;/a&gt; and am &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbarley.com/&quot;&gt;currently developing the coolest thing&lt;/a&gt; I have ever worked on. Not a day goes by that I am not grateful for this opportunity and excited to see where it goes. If you would like to hear more about this story, feel free to check out the podcast &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chasingproduct.com/episodes/episode-10-first-dont-succeed-product-launch-wtim-whitacre&quot;&gt;Chasing Product&lt;/a&gt; which I was a guest on earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things I wish I did this year and more on my list for 2014 but I am happy to report that it is a very nice feeling to end a year with few regrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have a bucket list... but I&amp;#39;m not dead yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/12/31/year-in-review-2013.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/12/31/year-in-review-2013.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current Loves : Reading Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While I don't read as many books as I want (or buy), I do spend quite a bit of time reading on a weekly basis. Listed below is a list of what I'm currently digging. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenews.im&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The News&lt;/a&gt; by Ahmet Sülek - A mix of Designer News &amp; Hacker News&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;iOS&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/interesting-for-iphone/id586848801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Interesting&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Rundle - A mix of a ton of great sites... never be bored again. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; - Keeps me up on current web trends&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indievisionmusic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Indie Vision Music&lt;/a&gt; - A way to stay up to date with my favorite artists&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://colin.getbarley.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Colin Devroe's Blog&lt;/a&gt; - Yeah, he's a friend but he's a good writer and shares some awesome stuff&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt; - My favorite web comic, smart &amp; witty&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web / iOS&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpocket.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pocket App&lt;/a&gt; - Not specific content, but anything else I find throughout the day, I send here for later&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dribbble.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt; - While not much reading here, it's still a great site to keep up with&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/12/16/current-loves-reading-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/12/16/current-loves-reading-edition.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Terminal Setup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.getbarley.com/2791/development-tools-updated&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, I switched back to the OS X built in terminal for my everyday coding needs. I like to keep as few programs on my computer as possible and since terminal is baked in, I just stick with it. One thing I missed was some of the customization I got when using programs such as iTerm. To combat that, I began looking around for some ways to trick out my terminal, both in appearance but also (and more importantly) in functionality.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First step, download and install &lt;a href=&quot;http://totalterminal.binaryage.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TotalTerminal&lt;/a&gt;. While this is technically another program, you only know it by the extra settings window under Terminal &gt; Preferences. This program adds the ability to open the terminal window from the top/bottom of your screen with a simple key command. I'm currently using CMD + Left Arrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to the meat of my terminal window, I have chosen to use the Zsh shell as opposed to the built in Bash shell. Added to this, I also use &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetargon.com/who-we-are/robby-russell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Robby Russell&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oh-My-Zsh&lt;/a&gt; framework which is where most customization comes in. I won't go into much setup here as this has already been done &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevendobbelaere.be/installing-and-configuring-the-oh-my-zsh-shell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many times&lt;/a&gt; before, but it's fairly easy. Just install Zsh, followed by Oh-My-Zsh and start configuring the .zshrc file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is what mine looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# Path to your oh-my-zsh configuration.&lt;br /&gt;ZSH=$HOME/.oh-my-zsh&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Theme&lt;br /&gt;ZSH_THEME=&quot;cloud&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Aliases&lt;br /&gt;alias zshconfig=&quot;subl ~/.zshrc&quot;&lt;br /&gt;alias ohmyzsh=&quot;subl ~/.oh-my-zsh&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Waiting Dots&lt;br /&gt;COMPLETION_WAITING_DOTS=&quot;true&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Plugins&lt;br /&gt;plugins=(git)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;source $ZSH/oh-my-zsh.sh&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I keep things pretty simple. I use the cloud theme, have a few alias set up and am currently only using the GIT plugin. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/wiki/Plugins&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MANY other plugins&lt;/a&gt; you can use as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There you have it, my simple terminal setup. Not too many frills, but between the key command to open terminal, and the GIT plugin to always know what branch I'm on and if there are uncommitted changes it makes for quite a nice daily work environment. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/12/15/my-terminal-setup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/12/15/my-terminal-setup.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code &amp; Tonic on GitHub</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About 2 months ago, I launched a new website - &lt;a href=&quot;http://codeandtonic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Code &amp; Tonic&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoy blogging but rarely &lt;del&gt;get&lt;/del&gt; make time to sit down and do it. So, I had the idea to create a simple website where I could share sites, articles and products that I find awesome but don't want to write an entire article about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I decided to make the code available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twhitacre/code-and-tonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;  Even though I took an &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/themes/required&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;existing awesome WordPress theme&lt;/a&gt; and turned it into a Barley theme, I still felt it might help some people who are getting started with Barley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twhitacre/code-and-tonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; and download it if you'd like. As always, feed back is appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/10/29/code-tonic-on-github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/10/29/code-tonic-on-github.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>