<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tim Whitacre</title>
    <description>Code. Music. Life.</description>    
    <link>http://timw.co</link>
    <atom:link href="http://timw.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging Platforms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As an instructor at &lt;a href=&quot;http://theironyard.com&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/a&gt;, I get asked this question a lot. Here is a VERY simple breakdown of some of my thoughts on different platforms. This is by no means comprehensive, but I feel it gives a pretty solid overview of the platforms I&amp;#39;ve had experience with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to set up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up and running really quick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple themes to choose from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom Domain Support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not very editable without paying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fairly generic looking (not really a bad thing though)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to set up and use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple themes to choose from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom domain support
*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes not taken seriously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://medium.com/&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely social&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No custom domain support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not customizable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only one &amp;quot;theme&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully customizable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be time consuming your first time to set up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Costs (you need hosting and a domain)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to manage it and keep it up to date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://getbarley.com&quot;&gt;Barley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upsides - &lt;em&gt;spoiler alert, I had a hand in building this&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely Customizable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosted for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropbox Sync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple to use template tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You still need to touch HTML if you want it customized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has a higher monthly cost than some others listed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely customizable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostable on Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static site, so it&amp;#39;s really fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Downsides&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not super easy to work with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different than normal workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/09/26/blogging-platforms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/09/26/blogging-platforms.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are past the halfway mark for the first Front End class in Atlanta. We are moving fast and everyone is keeping up in an incredible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have walked through a handful of tools, libraries and frameworks. We have also spent a good amount of time talking through programming theory and best practice. One of the pieces that makes The Iron Yard stand out is that we put a large focus on learning how to learn. Let’s face it, in 12 weeks we can’t even begin to cover every library and framework and every aspect of HTML5. Let’s not forget about what’s coming in ECMAScript 6. Sure we’ve talked about it, but more importantly, we’ve talked about the fact that it’s coming and how it won’t stop there. New frameworks are coming out every week and the best way to keep up is to learn what to look for. It helps to have a broad enough understanding of the language to break it down and judge for yourself if it will be useful to you or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, we still dive pretty deep into JavaScript core. We spent a while writing vanilla JavaScript before we introduced jQuery, Underscore and a handful of other libraries. We also talked through the myriad of MV* frameworks and currently we are walking through Backbone.js. We start here because it is a library with a low barrier to entry. It helps round out the idea of JavaScript constructors and gives us a great way to organize our code for building applications. We are about a week into Backbone and each student in the class is building their own version of a blog. This might sound like a simple project to a few of you, but keep in mind that 6 weeks ago many of our students had never opened a text editor before. That, to me, is incredible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the only way this can be accomplished is because of the immersive environment that The Iron Yard provides. After all, perseverance does pay off and working hard for something you want is a great feeling. Even as the instructor of the class, I’m learning more about programming and myself with each lecture. I am falling more in love with this craft each day and glad to have a group of people along for the ride with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://atlanta.theironyard.com/post/92757229935/always-learning&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard Blog : Atlanta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/08/17/learning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/08/17/learning.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Perseverance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is hard to believe Atlanta’s first Front End Engineering class is now finishing their fourth week. I think back to the dinner we had together the night before class began. Here was a group coming from all over, meeting for the first time and embarking on a twelve week journey. We all came from different backgrounds, states, and skill levels; yet we all shared a common commitment to grow and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any legendary journey, the most rewarding roads are also the most difficult. By the third week of class, I began to notice tired eyes and messed up hair - probably the result of sleeping on campus the night before. Many became weary in their exploration, their discouragement obvious from their sighs as they stared at their monitor or the open conversation they had with me about their struggles. As much as I wanted to tell them to take a week off, I knew that reaching our destination in twelve weeks would mean pushing forward to the end goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we pushed forward and were rewarded with week four. Frustration melted to excitement. The concepts we had been covering were just now starting to click. Not just in programming, but in all areas of life, it is a proud moment when you invest in mastering something for a long time and it finally begins to work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the students were really starting to understand what they were doing, and knowing I wanted to keep pushing them, we spent part of the fourth week doing their first group project. Students divided into three groups and I gave them a wireframe and a fairly vague project summary and sent them off running. Not only would they have to utilize all of the skills they have learned so far but find a way to use these in a team setting. Up until now all of their work has been solo. It has been incredible to see how they are all coming together, dividing up tasks and even implementing some agile development methods to get their work done. They are learning to communicate with each other and what it means to work as part of a team. They have been able to use their creativity to think outside the box and explore some things that I don’t think we would have specifically covered in a lecture. Once they finish the project they will be presenting them to the class and sharing what worked and what didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week has been a welcome retreat from the struggles of the first three weeks. Don’t get me wrong, we still have a LOT to cover in the next eight weeks and I expect more frustration, hair pulling, and perplexing stares at their screen. The reality is that in the journey of programming, there are always moments of frustration and hitting one’s head against the wall. New tools and processes come out every day and we have to keep up. But I hope my students will join me in saying that the hard perseverance of week three met with the glory of week four is what makes being a developer so enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://atlanta.theironyard.com/post/92049505715/perseverance-pays-off&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard Blog : Atlanta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/07/01/perserverance-pays-off.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/07/01/perserverance-pays-off.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Joining the Iron Yard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the privilege over the years to work with some amazing companies and startups and am excited to bring my experiences into the classroom. For me, being able to spend my days building and talking about development is a dream come true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first got into programming about 12 years ago and had to learn everything on my own. There was no Iron Yard, no online training and just a few books I could find at the library. Even then I still found that the best way to learn was to immerse myself and to actually build something. It wasn’t too long after that I developed my first app, began attending JavaScript conferences and started to feel like a part of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming to The Iron Yard is exciting for two reasons. First (and most importantly) it is because they are an awesome company filled with great people and amazing students. I’ve only been around campus for a week but spending time with some of the current students has been one of the best parts. Listening to stories of what they are learning, what they are struggling with and what they are planning to build has been very humbling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, it’s the south. I was born in Florida and lived the first 18 years of my life in a warmer climate and am excited to be back. Living in the north was definitely an experience and one that I won’t soon forget but from the day my wife and I got married we’ve constantly talked about moving south. In the past week, I not only sold my snow blower but also tried boiled peanuts for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/06/05/joining-the-iron-yard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/06/05/joining-the-iron-yard.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Something Crazy</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to challenge you to do something crazy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the first line in an email I received less than 1 month after the startup I was at ran into some trouble. And crazy it is, but also very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Steph and I are moving to Atlanta.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to become a part of such an amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://theironyard.com/about/team/&quot;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; but also for all of the opportunity that Atlanta brings for both of us. I might write more about this in the months to come, but for now just read &lt;a href=&quot;http://stephwhitacre.com/chasing-dream/&quot;&gt;Steph&amp;#39;s post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I just want to publicly thank all of our friends and family who have been so incredibly helpful this last week. We could not do this without you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/05/13/something-crazy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/05/13/something-crazy.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Year for Whisk(e)y</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/timwco&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/timwco&quot;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; you know that I like to indulge once in a while. So far my drink of choice has been gin. &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/jkzy3AJG50/&quot;&gt;Plymouth Gin&lt;/a&gt; to be exact. As great as gin is, I have been told I should be drinking whiskey, at least some of the time. This includes all forms, bourbon, scotch, irish, rye and the likes. I’ll be honest, so far my favorite is rye with scotch being a close second but I have a long list to try and will hopefully be adding to the list as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even my wife is pushing me towards it by getting me the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Drink-More-Whiskey-Everything-Favorite/dp/1452109745&quot;&gt;Drink More Whiskey&lt;/a&gt; as well as some nice &lt;a href=&quot;http://buck4men.bigcartel.com/product/buck-signature-low-ball-glass&quot;&gt;low ball glasses&lt;/a&gt;, whiskey stones and everything else one might need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So without further ado, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/whiskey&quot;&gt;my whiskey list&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to hear your feedback. Is there something obvious I’ve missed or a small craft distillery I’ve not heard of? If you have any suggestions, hit me up on twitter as I’d love to see what else is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/04/01/the-year-for-whiskey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/04/01/the-year-for-whiskey.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So Many Bookmarks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t have to tell you this, but there is a lot of stuff on the internet. Obviously most of it is junk, but there is a lot of great content. This begs the question, “how do I consume it all” or rather, “how do I consume as much as I can that is relevant to me so I can keep up to speed in my industry”. This is not an easy task and because content and the way content is presented continually changes, you almost have no choice but to use some sort of service to help you keep up with it all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it is an aggregation service like &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenews.im/&quot;&gt;thenews.im&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyosity.com/interesting/&quot;&gt;interesting app&lt;/a&gt;, whatever your poison it still doesn’t help with things your friends, co-workers and twitter users share. You need a way to trap that content so when you have a chance to take a break you haven’t forgotten it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In walks &lt;a href=&quot;https://unmark.it&quot;&gt;Unmark&lt;/a&gt;. Many may have guessed I would talk about this eventually as I had a hand in building it, but I was part of this build because I knew the way I was saving my bookmarks was broken. Every service I used, while many were good, they still missed something. I’ve found that they just fill up with links I never visit again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this situation for example: I’m sitting at my desk working and a co-worker says I should read this article. I don’t want to stop what I’m doing but is throwing it into one of these services the best idea. I’m not even sure what the article is about and not sure if I really am interested in it. This is the same for videos, code examples and any other link that is shared or I stumble upon throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, IMO is why Unmark is so awesome. Our tagline for it is ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://unmark.it&quot;&gt;The to do app for your bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;”. This means as a piece of content comes along during the day, I can simply throw it into my Unmark account. Later that night from my iPad or phone I can go through the list of marks I saved and see if they really are as good as I first thought. If they are, I can send them to be read later, or watch the video right inside of Unmark. If it is a recipe, I can look at the ingredient list and determine if I want to put in in a recipe storage app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Unmark can be used in many different ways, this is how I use it and I have found it has changed the way I view content and the content I do end up consuming is more relevant and meaningful to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/03/28/so-many-bookmarks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/03/28/so-many-bookmarks.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scranton… Meet CoalWork</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coworking is not a new concept at all. In fact not too long ago while working from home I was doing a ton of research for a coworking spot in this area. Unfortunately there wasn’t one… or at least one that I could be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, anyone reading this who isn’t local might not realize that Scranton (and the surrounding area) is not a very technical place. I would even say that there are not really many tech companies in the area either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/PBs0tS46TlyZlmOGw7vl&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, some of the guys I work with are trying to change that. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://coalwork.com&quot;&gt;CoalWork&lt;/a&gt;, a forthcoming coworking spot. We are still in the early stages but hope this will become a staple in city. We hope through this we’ll meet some awesome people, learn some new things and possibly even change the way this area views tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is interested, feel free to check out the website or follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/coalwork&quot;&gt;CoalWork on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/02/25/scranton%E2%80%A6-meet-coalwork.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/02/25/scranton%E2%80%A6-meet-coalwork.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current Loves : iOS Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s finally starting to warm up here in Northeast PA and I’m neck deep in finishing a soon to be released update to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unmarkit&quot;&gt;Unmark&lt;/a&gt; (formerly nilai.co).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get asked quite often by friends what are the most used apps on my iPhone. I thought this would be a great place to share them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image below is a screenshot of my actual home screen on my iPhone 5. I’ve had it this way for probably the last 6 months and don’t plan to change anytime soon. Although with the thousands of app developers out there… that could change tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a breakdown of some of my favorite apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/6EeMF8uORle55vGcbtrr&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo App - &lt;a href=&quot;http://campl.us/&quot;&gt;Camera Plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/mobile/ios.html&quot;&gt;Chrome for iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather - &lt;a href=&quot;http://checktheweather.co/&quot;&gt;Check the Weather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anylistapp.com/&quot;&gt;AnyList&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reader - &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/ios/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pod Catcher - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shiftyjelly.com/pocketcasts&quot;&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music - &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/rdio/id335060889&quot;&gt;Rdio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News - &lt;a href=&quot;http://flyosity.com/interesting/&quot;&gt;Interesting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail - Default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendar - Default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also do keep up on some social sites like Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and Foursquare and thus they landed a spot on my home screen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also many others I didn’t mention. If you have any questions or wonder what any are, feel free to hit me up on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timwco&quot;&gt;tweetbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/02/20/current-loves-ios-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/02/20/current-loves-ios-edition.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on Email</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First, let me clarify my relationship with email. When it comes the jobs I’ve had, I went from working in an office, to working from home, doing freelance and now back in an office. It might not sound like much of a switch, but each one required different levels of communication to stay up to speed. For instance, my first office job was in a building that had about 150 employees. Not huge, but a lot of people were not close by. When it came to the developers and designers I was currently sharing a project with, we used instant message, but when it came to people in a different division (or people I’d rather not talk to that often) email came in mighty handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I left my first office job, and started working from home I realized that I would need to step up my email game. Again, anyone I was working with very closely, we kept in contact through IM or a chatroom like Campfire. The difference this time was not the size of the company (only about 10 people) but rather the fact that sometimes something was just too long to say in a quick message. At my office job, I would walk over to that person, pull up a chair and have a conversation. From home, this wasn’t possible. My options were either Skype or email. Since Skype takes a minimum of 10 minutes and 5 crashes before successfully starting, I usually chose email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today. I’m back working full time in an office. This time however, the team is small at only 7 people, with 5 of them being in earshot of me all day long. More important than this though, we’ve started using a program called &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; (which I highly recommend) and it has all but rid my need of email for the work I’m currently doing. We also use other tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; and Google Docs. All of this combined there isn’t much reason for me to open email at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on my current situation, I am going to try something. This has been suggested many times before by other people in a variety of ways, but starting today, I’m only going to check my email 3 times a day. I’m going to attempt to check it morning, noon and afternoon/evening. This way, I can still get back to people in a timely fashion but the constant barrage or email flooding in throughout the day won’t distract me from what I’m currently trying to accomplish. The only time I will break this is if someone needs something and I have to send it via email or if someone specifically tells me to check my email for an attachment. Otherwise, they will have to wait to get a response from me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, my biggest issue is not email from friends, family or co-workers, but rather the fringe email that makes its way in. I’ve signed up for quite a few newsletters over the years. Many I’m still happy to be a part of and a few that I wish would just let me unsubscribe. The problem isn’t that I don’t want to read them, but rather that I do. I want to see the updates on the new app coming out, and I want to read what some of my friends wrote about, but I don’t NEED to read about it right now. I’ve begun treating email like a glorified checklist of items I need to work through, with the goal of having all accomplished (archived or deleted). This means if one comes in while I’m working on something, the tendency is to jump over and take care of it. By removing the constant thread of email coming in throughout the day and limiting it to a few times a day, I can easily stay focused and possibly even reduce some stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always hit me up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timwco&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, as I’ll usually respond much quicker there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2014/02/10/thoughts-on-email.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2014/02/10/thoughts-on-email.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Year In Review : 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This time of year, there are thousands of articles (likely more) being written with a similar title or one relating to next years resolutions. I know they are cliched and most people don&amp;#39;t really care all that much, but I did write an article at &lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.getbarley.com/2790/doing-more&quot;&gt;the beginning of this year&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to put out a recap of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article I&amp;#39;m referring to is titled &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.getbarley.com/2790/doing-more&quot;&gt;Doing More&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; and it was this idea that over the course of 2013 and all years following I would simply put a focus on doing bigger and better things each year. I also outlined quite a few goals such as loosing weight, reading more and doing things that I&amp;#39;ve always wanted. Unfortunately, I didn&amp;#39;t loose as much as I wanted this year, so that is one that I need to continue to work on. I did read more... a lot more actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did in 2013 that I have always wanted to do was going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/p/ZD00alJGw9&quot;&gt;Yosemite&lt;/a&gt;. Let me first say if you haven&amp;#39;t been there, start planning a trip right now, it is worth every penny. When I wrote that article, I had no idea that I would have the opportunity to go. Shortly into the month of January I realized that my wife and I had not been on a vacation (just the two of us) since our honeymoon 6+ years prior. I knew I needed to plan something but never thought it would have been to go across the country to one of the most beautiful places on earth. In short, it was life changing and I would go back every year (or week) if I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the biggest thing that happened to me this year was I officially jumped ship from the services industry to the product industry. I left my comfortable job of developing websites and apps for other people and joined an &lt;a href=&quot;http://plainmade.com/&quot;&gt;awesome team&lt;/a&gt; and am &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbarley.com/&quot;&gt;currently developing the coolest thing&lt;/a&gt; I have ever worked on. Not a day goes by that I am not grateful for this opportunity and excited to see where it goes. If you would like to hear more about this story, feel free to check out the podcast &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chasingproduct.com/episodes/episode-10-first-dont-succeed-product-launch-wtim-whitacre&quot;&gt;Chasing Product&lt;/a&gt; which I was a guest on earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things I wish I did this year and more on my list for 2014 but I am happy to report that it is a very nice feeling to end a year with few regrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have a bucket list... but I&amp;#39;m not dead yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/12/31/year-in-review-2013.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/12/31/year-in-review-2013.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Current Loves : Reading Edition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While I don&#39;t read as many books as I want (or buy), I do spend quite a bit of time reading on a weekly basis. Listed below is a list of what I&#39;m currently digging. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenews.im&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The News&lt;/a&gt; by Ahmet Sülek - A mix of Designer News &amp; Hacker News&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;iOS&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/interesting-for-iphone/id586848801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Interesting&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Rundle - A mix of a ton of great sites... never be bored again. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; - Keeps me up on current web trends&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indievisionmusic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Indie Vision Music&lt;/a&gt; - A way to stay up to date with my favorite artists&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://colin.getbarley.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Colin Devroe&#39;s Blog&lt;/a&gt; - Yeah, he&#39;s a friend but he&#39;s a good writer and shares some awesome stuff&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt; - My favorite web comic, smart &amp; witty&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web / iOS&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpocket.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pocket App&lt;/a&gt; - Not specific content, but anything else I find throughout the day, I send here for later&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Web&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dribbble.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt; - While not much reading here, it&#39;s still a great site to keep up with&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/12/16/current-loves-reading-edition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/12/16/current-loves-reading-edition.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Terminal Setup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&quot;http://tim.getbarley.com/2791/development-tools-updated&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, I switched back to the OS X built in terminal for my everyday coding needs. I like to keep as few programs on my computer as possible and since terminal is baked in, I just stick with it. One thing I missed was some of the customization I got when using programs such as iTerm. To combat that, I began looking around for some ways to trick out my terminal, both in appearance but also (and more importantly) in functionality.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First step, download and install &lt;a href=&quot;http://totalterminal.binaryage.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TotalTerminal&lt;/a&gt;. While this is technically another program, you only know it by the extra settings window under Terminal &gt; Preferences. This program adds the ability to open the terminal window from the top/bottom of your screen with a simple key command. I&#39;m currently using CMD + Left Arrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to the meat of my terminal window, I have chosen to use the Zsh shell as opposed to the built in Bash shell. Added to this, I also use &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetargon.com/who-we-are/robby-russell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Robby Russell&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oh-My-Zsh&lt;/a&gt; framework which is where most customization comes in. I won&#39;t go into much setup here as this has already been done &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevendobbelaere.be/installing-and-configuring-the-oh-my-zsh-shell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many times&lt;/a&gt; before, but it&#39;s fairly easy. Just install Zsh, followed by Oh-My-Zsh and start configuring the .zshrc file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is what mine looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# Path to your oh-my-zsh configuration.&lt;br /&gt;ZSH=$HOME/.oh-my-zsh&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Theme&lt;br /&gt;ZSH_THEME=&quot;cloud&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Aliases&lt;br /&gt;alias zshconfig=&quot;subl ~/.zshrc&quot;&lt;br /&gt;alias ohmyzsh=&quot;subl ~/.oh-my-zsh&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Waiting Dots&lt;br /&gt;COMPLETION_WAITING_DOTS=&quot;true&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Plugins&lt;br /&gt;plugins=(git)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;source $ZSH/oh-my-zsh.sh&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I keep things pretty simple. I use the cloud theme, have a few alias set up and am currently only using the GIT plugin. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/wiki/Plugins&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MANY other plugins&lt;/a&gt; you can use as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There you have it, my simple terminal setup. Not too many frills, but between the key command to open terminal, and the GIT plugin to always know what branch I&#39;m on and if there are uncommitted changes it makes for quite a nice daily work environment. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/12/15/my-terminal-setup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/12/15/my-terminal-setup.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code &amp; Tonic on GitHub</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About 2 months ago, I launched a new website - &lt;a href=&quot;http://codeandtonic.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Code &amp; Tonic&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoy blogging but rarely &lt;del&gt;get&lt;/del&gt; make time to sit down and do it. So, I had the idea to create a simple website where I could share sites, articles and products that I find awesome but don&#39;t want to write an entire article about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I decided to make the code available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twhitacre/code-and-tonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;  Even though I took an &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org/themes/required&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;existing awesome WordPress theme&lt;/a&gt; and turned it into a Barley theme, I still felt it might help some people who are getting started with Barley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twhitacre/code-and-tonic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt; and download it if you&#39;d like. As always, feed back is appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/10/29/code-tonic-on-github.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/10/29/code-tonic-on-github.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I Love Trello</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m one of those guys who&#39;s always writing down ideas for new projects. Generally these are projects that will push a certain skill of mine to the next level. Sometimes, however they are simply something that I just want to do to for fun with no specific agenda.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/gJOqRfvUQgipO7tYWg8X&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was looking for an easy way to organize these &quot;projects&quot; and tried about every free version of a project management tool I could find. In the end, I came back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;. It has served me well in the past and to be honest, I&#39;m not really sure why I didn&#39;t go with it in the first place. After about an hour of setting up a new board, I&#39;m happy to say I&#39;ve been able to not only organize my personal projects, but also prioritize them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/08/24/why-i-love-trello.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/08/24/why-i-love-trello.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Expanding My Toolbelt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When ever you start a new project it&#39;s very important to have the right tools. Today, I decided to tackle one of the many projects that has been looming over my head. Before I got started, I took a step back to figure out which tools I would need. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When doing a project around the house and realizing I need a tool that I currently don&#39;t have, it usually means a trip to Lowes and probably a lot of money. Luckily with the type of development I do, many (if not all) of the tools I need are free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are a few I got to install today (though to be fair, I&#39;ve used them all before... just not on this machine)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://getcomposer.org/&quot;&gt;Composer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://laravel.com/&quot;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://brew.sh/&quot;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.filepicker.io/api/file/OnbSz6kRg262Loaa3avA&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/08/24/expanding-my%C2%A0toolbelt.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/08/24/expanding-my%C2%A0toolbelt.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Barley Helper for Sublime Text</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s no&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;surprise&amp;nbsp;that I&#39;m a huge fan of Sublime Text and in fact most of &lt;a href=&quot;http://plainmade.com/blog/2740/the-tools-we-use&quot;&gt;the team&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I work with&amp;nbsp;uses it as well. When creating &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbarley.com/docs/templates&quot;&gt;Barley templates&lt;/a&gt;, we wanted a way to make it a little easier.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never created a Sublime Text plugin before, but found it to be fairly easy, especially the nature of this one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to check it out and let me know your thoughts. If you are a developer looking to create Barley templates, please &lt;a href=&quot;http://plainmade.com/blog/25/join-the-barley-farmhand-network&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;, and hopefully this will make your life a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download Here -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twhitacre/Barley-Sublime-Helper&quot;&gt;https://github.com/twhitacre/Barley-Sublime-Helper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/07/23/barley-helper-for-sublime-text.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/07/23/barley-helper-for-sublime-text.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing on Barley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started working for &lt;a href=&quot;http://plainmade.com&quot;&gt;Plain&lt;/a&gt; back in &lt;a href=&quot;http://plainmade.com/blog/2515/say-hello-to-tim&quot;&gt;May&lt;/a&gt;, but had been working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbarley.com/&quot;&gt;Barley&lt;/a&gt; since earlier this year. As with most developers, my website always gets neglected &lt;a href=&quot;http://asdf&quot;&gt;because&lt;/a&gt; after working all day long on client&#39;s websites, the last thing I want to do at night is work on mine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I finally had some time this weekend to set up my site on Barley... it took just a few hours. Going forward it will be much easier for me to continue to write and share my thoughts and possibly some code snippets here and there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, this is my first time actually using Barley outside of my testing. I&#39;m excited about this because it will let me feel what our users feel and allow me to focus my code on making the experience that much better.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/2013/07/14/writing-on-barley.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/2013/07/14/writing-on-barley.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Migrate from (dv) to (ve) Server</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Both my &lt;a href=&quot;http://argyllstudios.com&quot;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt; an I have been using Media Temple for years now. We started on their Grid Server (shared hosting) but quickly realized we needed a much better server. That&#39;s when we moved to their Dedicated Virtual (dv) server. We&#39;ve been running that for the past 3 years and have had no problems at all. In fact it&#39;s been the best hosting we&#39;ve ever had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though business is going well, we started looking at ways to save a little $$ here and there. We decided to re-evaluate our hosting platform and see how we could save money. After much consideration we decided to stick with MT since they&#39;ve always been so good to us, but decided to switch to their (ve) server. The specs are almost the same and it&#39;s almost half the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference? Basically with the (dv) you are not only paying for hosting but also for a Plesk license. It gives you a nice GUI for interacting with the server. Since we already work a ton with command line on our other severs we decided we didn&#39;t need this luxury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, enough with the back story. Here&#39;s the HOW you&#39;ve been waiting for. Keep in mind that this info is based around migrating from a (dv) to a (ve) server BUT it will help anyone looking to get started with MT&#39;s (ve) server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the info below is only for migrating a site to the (ve) and not how to &quot;set it up&quot;. If you are looking for that, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://donaldjenkins.com/2011/12/switching-from-a-dv-to-a-ve-server-on-media-temple/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. First things first, SSH into your server. (you can use any user that you&#39;ve set up or you can even use &#39;root&#39;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Create the new site in your virtual host (replace with your domain and IP address)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash] sudo vi /etc/apache2/sites-available/DOMAIN.COM [/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then add the following to the file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[plain]&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;VirtualHost YOUR-IP:80&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
ServerAdmin webmaster@DOMAIN.COM&lt;br /&gt;
ServerName DOMAIN.COM&lt;br /&gt;
ServerAlias www.DOMAIN.COM&lt;br /&gt;
DocumentRoot /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/html/&lt;br /&gt;
ErrorLog /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/logs/error.log&lt;br /&gt;
CustomLog /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/logs/access.log combined&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;/VirtualHost&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[/plain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll also need to know how to use Vi, and can find out more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.colostate.edu/helpdocs/vi.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;, but for know just know that &lt;strong&gt;:q&lt;/strong&gt; will QUIT the file and &lt;strong&gt;:wq&lt;/strong&gt; will WRITE it before you QUIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Now we need to create the directories we specified above &quot;html&quot; and &quot;logs&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash]&lt;br /&gt;
sudo mkdir -p /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/html&lt;br /&gt;
sudo mkdir -p /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/logs&lt;br /&gt;
[/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Then just add the site to Apache and reload it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash]&lt;br /&gt;
sudo a2ensite DOMAIN.COM&lt;br /&gt;
sudo /etc/init.d/apache2 reload&lt;br /&gt;
[/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Make the folder writeable use either 755 or 777 (just be cautious of security)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash] sudo chmod 777 /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/html [/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Copy over your files from your (dv) to your (ve) and verify it&#39;s all there - &lt;a href=&quot;http://ip-address/domain.com/html/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://ip-address/domain.com/html/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. Now comes the database part. If your site is database-less then you can move on to the last step otherwise see below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First log in to MySQL via command line (I prefer to log in with root)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash] mysql -u root -p [/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, create the database and set up a user and password&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash] create database DATABASE-NAME; grant all on DATABASE-NAME.* to &#39;USERNAME&#39; identified by &#39;PASSWORD&#39;; [/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, exit MySQL and import your .SQL file into the database. I personally found the easiest way to do this is to first upload your .SQL file to the root of your /html/ folder then run the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[bash] mysql -u root -p DATABASE-NAME &amp;lt; /var/www/DOMAIN.COM/html/FILENAME.SQL [/bash]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. Lastly, log into your OLD (dv) and remove the DNS Zone and then log into your new (ve) and add the new DNS Zone.... or you could just use MT&#39;s built in &lt;a href=&quot;http://kb.mediatemple.net/questions/1882/Using+the+Point+to+Another+Server+tool&quot;&gt;Point to Another Server Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That should be it... let me know if you have any issues or run into any problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2013/01/27/migrate-from-dv-to-ve-server.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2013/01/27/migrate-from-dv-to-ve-server.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Development Tools - Updated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite often, I get asked what kind of set up I have and what programs I use on a daily basis. About a year ago, I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/reboot/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, but below is an updated list... this time I&#39;ll stick to development related programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, below you&#39;ll find some info my current hardware setup as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://panic.com/coda/&quot;&gt;Coda 2&lt;/a&gt; - came out in 2012 and I&#39;ve been very pleased with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/2&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt; - even though Coda has been updated... I still turn to ST2 when I need nothing but pure speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mamp.info/en/mamp-pro/index.html&quot;&gt;MAMP Pro&lt;/a&gt; - running sites locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminal_(OS_X)&quot;&gt;Terminal&lt;/a&gt; - I used to use iTerm... but switched back since I feel this does a good enough job on it&#39;s own. Also, I use Coda 2&#39;s terminal as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://colorsnapper.com/&quot;&gt;ColorSnapper&lt;/a&gt; - grabs colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.binarynights.com/&quot;&gt;ForkLift&lt;/a&gt; - switched from Filezilla to ForkLift. Haven&#39;t looked back....&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; - even though it&#39;s a browser... it&#39;s one of the best tools a developer can have in his toolbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://adobe.com&quot;&gt;Fireworks CS3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://adobe.com&quot;&gt;Photoshop CS6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apple.com&quot;&gt;2009 iMac&lt;/a&gt; - 16gb Ram, 500gb Hard Drive - 2 monitors connected to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apple.com&quot;&gt;2012 Macbook Pro 15&quot; Retina&lt;/a&gt; - 8gb Ram, 256gb Hard Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apple.com&quot;&gt;iPhone 5&lt;/a&gt; - 16gb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/devices/details?id=nexus_7_16gb&quot;&gt;Google Nexus 7&lt;/a&gt; 16gb (my only non apple device - everyone should have at least one!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2013/01/04/dev-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2013/01/04/dev-tools.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Doing More</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Twenty years from now you will be more disappointed by the things that you didn&#39;t do than by the ones you did do. So throw off the bowlines. Sail away from the safe harbor. Catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore. Dream. Discover.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Mark Twain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above quote is one that my wife tends to use a lot, and for good reason. Honestly, I had never heard it until she brought it to my attention. I&#39;ve spent the last few days reading it over and over and realizing that there is so much more to life than sitting at my desk programming. Don&#39;t get me wrong, I thoroughly enjoy programming and my job... actually I can go as far to say that I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a little over 3 years ago, I left an &quot;office&quot; job for a &quot;at home&quot; job. I can&#39;t tell you how excited I was, just knowing I would be able to spend more time with my wife... finally be able to get a dog and put more focus on things I had been distracted from. The only problem was... I was wrong. Well I do spend more time with my wife and we did get a dog... but all I&#39;ve done for the past 3 years is program. I&#39;ve launched a few side projects but my grand and glorious plans of &quot;doing&quot; more has been a complete flop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not a big fan of New Year&#39;s Resolutions... because they tend to remind me what failure feels like. This year, instead of making a list of resolutions... I&#39;m making one. It&#39;s a pretty big one, but also one that is very very hard to fail at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My 2013 New Year&#39;s Resolutions is to simply.... Do More.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loose &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; weight...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; active...&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to be &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; efficient...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love people &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; time doing the things I&#39;ve always wanted to...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it... I just want this year and every year to come to be filled with more than any other year prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to die without a bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2013/01/02/doing-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2013/01/02/doing-more.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Move:DC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I had an opportunity to head to Washington DC (first time) with some friends to be part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://invisiblechildren.com/movedc/&quot;&gt;Move:DC&lt;/a&gt; put on by &lt;a href=&quot;http://invisiblechildren.com&quot;&gt;Invisible Children&lt;/a&gt;. This event was part of their year long movement to bring Joseph Kony to justice... also known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://invisiblechildren.com/movedc/&quot;&gt;Kony 2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have been supporting IC for the past 4 years and have been very proud to do so. For those of you who don&#39;t know, they exist to help bring restitution to those affected by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lord&#39;s_Resistance_Army&quot;&gt;LRA&lt;/a&gt;. So far, they are doing a really good job. I won&#39;t go into specifics, since you can read all the updates on their website, but I&#39;ll just say that things are happening and in this dark world we live in, it&#39;s great to be a part of something that is making a difference. Even if only one life was saved (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lracrisistracker.com/&quot;&gt;and there have been many&lt;/a&gt;), it would all be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-373&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0014&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0014-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-372&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0012&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0012-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2012/11/19/movedc.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2012/11/19/movedc.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guitars &amp; Pedals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-370 alignright&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0005&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0005-224x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;224&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;It&#39;s no secret that I thoroughly enjoy &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenoiselounge.com&quot;&gt;music&lt;/a&gt;, but many may not know that I also play myself. I have the privilege of co-leading the student band at &lt;a href=&quot;http://parkerhill.org&quot;&gt;our church&lt;/a&gt; on a weekly basis and getting to lead a group of up to 75 middle school students in worship every Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing about me is I&#39;m a gear hound... I can never seem to have enough. While I consider myself very good with our finances, I do have a week spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, I&#39;ve been re-building my pedal board and somehow in the middle of it all, I also picked up a new guitar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll start with the guitar. It&#39;s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibanez.com/HollowBodyGuitars/model-AS73&quot;&gt;Ibanez Artcore AS73&lt;/a&gt;, a semi-hollow body guitar that sounds just as pretty as it looks. Since I play a variety of different types of music, I needed something that was a little less aggressive than my current guitar (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.schecterguitars.com/International/Vault/15/C-1-ELITE-2001-2007.aspx&quot;&gt;Schecter C1-Elite&lt;/a&gt;) and I just happened to find this guitar for a steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my bank account recovered from that purchase, I went back to finalizing my pedal board... for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll break it down for you based off of the signal chain (from my guitar to my amp).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-374&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0015&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0015-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Korg Pitch Black Tuner - best tuner I&#39;ve ever used... especially on a dark stage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHO Clone - this is similar to an EP Booster... it gives my signal a boost while preserving the sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMATMODS Brownie - this is one of the best overdrive pedals I&#39;ve ever played. I keep the drive down low and use it for less aggressive songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fulltone OCD - this is my second overdrive pedal and I use it for more aggressive songs. It can go from a sweet overdrive to a crushing distortion all while sounding unbelievable. I will never have a pedal board without this one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ernie Ball Passive Volume Pedal - controls volume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boss DD5 (with external tap tempo I built myself) - I keep this on the dotted eighth note setting and tap in the tempo of the song we are playing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boss RV5 - I&#39;m not HUGE on reverb, but I do like this pedal a lot. I generally keep it on the modulation setting but changed it up every now and then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, I run from my RV5 to a Line 6 POD 2.0 and essentially use that as my amp. I use the Vox AC 15 setting and I&#39;ve very happy with the overall sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/music/2012/10/03/guitars-and-pedals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/music/2012/10/03/guitars-and-pedals.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Produce Brands</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Life tends to stay pretty hectic.... and I rarely have time to pick up new projects. However, when a good friend approached me with a new idea a month or so back, I knew I would be a fool not to go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t go into too much detail as of yet... but basically I&#39;ll say this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EVERYONE eats produce... from one place or another and with all the new technology out there, the produce game is changing. We recognize that and also see an opportunity to create a product that will help make the lives of both consumers and growers better. You could say we are bridging a gap between the grower and the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll be releasing more details later but in the meantime though, enjoy this picture of some homemade sauce we made while discussing the product and be sure to check out our website - &lt;a href=&quot;http://producebrands.com&quot;&gt;http://producebrands.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-371&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0006&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0006-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/life/2012/08/10/produce-brands.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/life/2012/08/10/produce-brands.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer Fun</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-365 alignright&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_0004&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_0004-300x224.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;224&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer I had the awesome opportunity to go on a trip with a group of students from &lt;a href=&quot;http://parkerhill.org&quot;&gt;our church&lt;/a&gt;. The trip is called iPac and last for two weeks. The first part of the trip was a serving part, where the students helped build a home for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.habitatbirmingham.org/&quot;&gt;Habitat for Humanity of Greater Birmingham&lt;/a&gt;. The second week was spent at a camp in Panama City Beach, Florida called &lt;a href=&quot;http://bigstuf.com/&quot;&gt;BigStuf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege to join the students for the second week (yes I know... the easy part), but it was still well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is yet just another reason as to why I love how my church does student ministry, and am so grateful to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2012/07/02/summer-fun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2012/07/02/summer-fun.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WordPress - Get Rounded # of Posts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;ve written about this before, but decided to post it up here for your (and my) sake as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-350&quot; title=&quot;healthyFoodsRoundedNumber&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/healthyFoodsRoundedNumber.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;456&quot; height=&quot;176&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a client who had a massive amount of articles on his website and by using a content aggregation (a Google nightmare), he was adding more and more by the minute. Because of the vast number of articles, he wanted a way to show his visitors the size of his site but wanted it to look a little prettier than just counting all posts. We both agreed that the best way to handle this would be to display the posts rounded to the nearest hundred, since that is most commonly what he would say in passing when someone asked him about his blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/880123.js?file=roundedNumber.php&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2012/03/20/wordpress-get-rounded-of-posts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2012/03/20/wordpress-get-rounded-of-posts.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Responsive Design Question</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First off.... if you are unfamiliar with the term &quot;responsive web design&quot; (RWD) check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alistapart.com&quot;&gt;A List Apart&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s article on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/responsive-web-design/&quot;&gt;responsive web design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that that&#39;s out of the way. I&#39;d like to take a look at a recent issue brought up by a client I was working with. In building out their website with &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/&quot;&gt;fluid grids&lt;/a&gt; and RWD, we came across a small issue. That issue was that when a visitor of the website was using a tablet, phone or any smaller-dimension browsing device, there was no way for them to get back to a full site view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/largeGrid.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-342&quot; title=&quot;largeGrid&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/largeGrid.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;615&quot; height=&quot;242&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may sound a little strange, but it got me thinking. Remember when mobile versions of a website because really popular? Remember when &lt;a href=&quot;http://jquerymobile.com/&quot;&gt;jQuery mobile&lt;/a&gt; came out? Both of these solutions came about because we wanted an easy way to present our websites to clients on smaller devices, especially phones. While iPhones and Android browsers are great, sometimes you want a smaller version of the website to quickly navigate around and get the information you came seeking. Unfortunately not everyone has the money or really even needs a full blown native mobile app, but pretty much everyone these days should consider some sort of mobile solution. This is what spawned the mobile version of websites and ultimately the need for responsive design. Shortly after the creation of mobile version websites, developers needed a way to give the visitor the ability to go back to the &quot;desktop version&quot; of a site while on their phones. This is because generally speaking, a mobile version of a website is quite a bit different than the desktop version. Usually there are less images and less interactive features. Mobile websites generally focus more on content than anything else. The idea is to give the reader a quick overview or snapshot of what your company does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to my original problem. When creating a website using RWD, does one need to include a way to go back to a desktop version? You see, a mobile version a lot of times sits on a subdomain like &lt;em&gt;mobile.domain.com&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;m.domain.com&lt;/em&gt;. With RWD, there is no &quot;other version&quot; of the website but rather you use &lt;a href=&quot;http://reference.sitepoint.com/css/mediaqueries&quot;&gt;CSS3 media queries&lt;/a&gt; to determine how the content is portrayed to the visitor depending on the dimensions of their browsing window. Since it&#39;s not a separate version of the site, how and more importantly should you include a way to go back to a full desktop version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/smallGrid.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-341&quot; title=&quot;smallGrid&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/smallGrid.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;615&quot; height=&quot;158&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started using RWD over a year ago, I didn&#39;t ever consider this. I figured since we would still be showing the exact same site with just little bit less flair, the visitor didn&#39;t need a way to &quot;go back&quot;. Recently though, as many companies are embracing this technology, I find myself more and more frustrated that I can&#39;t view certain sites on my iPhone the way they were originally meant to be viewed. There is not way to go back. After having a brief discussion with this client I&#39;m currently working with, they decided they did want a way to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To not drag this on any further, I&#39;ve decided that it&#39;s much better to just give the visitors the choice. How can this be handled? Well there are many ways to tackle this from a programming standpoint. The BEST way, in my opinion, is to take care of it using your server-side language and setting either a temporary cookie or using a session to create an ID on the body tag that will override all of the media queries and thus presenting the site in its original format. It&#39;s not a small task, but once you build it into the framework of your choice, it will be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to do this on my website, which currently utilizes RWD, but when I get time I&#39;ll post up the code example of how I did it in case you are wondering. In the meantime, feel post a comment below or share your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2012/03/03/responsive-design-question.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2012/03/03/responsive-design-question.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reboot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it&#39;s that time again. It comes once a year or so. The time to reformat your hard drive and get your computer as clean as a whistle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know about you,  but over time I download and install many different apps and then uninstall just about as many. That leaves my computer hating me. I can sense it getting more and more frustrated every time I drag a new application into the folder. Well not anymore. Today it&#39;s smiling right back at me. With a squeaky clean hard drive and a fresh updated OS (Lion) my computer is ruining on all cylinders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also get a lot of people asking me quite often what I use as far as programs go. Well, when I decided to do my reboot, I made a list of all the programs I needed for daily work before I wiped them so I&#39;d have a reference to look back on. I&#39;ve decided to share it below... broken up into category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope someone else finds this useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; System Programs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean My Mac - very important. It keeps my mac running very smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropbox - for sharing files between co-workers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iBank - keeps my finances in order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLC - the only way to watch movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carbonite - gotta keep things backed up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sublime Text 2 - wicked fast development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coda - still pretty good... but slowly moving away from it for the one above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MAMP Pro - gotta have mamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequal Pro - my favorite way to interact with my database locally and some online ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTerm - better version of Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ColorSnapper - grabs colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filezilla - fastest FTP program I&#39;ve ever used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Stuff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evernote - keeps things in sync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pages - great word processor... much better than Word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photo and Slicing Programs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fireworks CS3 - I like this version the best&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoshop CS5 - I finally upgraded and so far so good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than a few other random programs, that&#39;s all I run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/life/2012/02/22/reboot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/life/2012/02/22/reboot.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DuckDuckGo ... just works!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-250 alignright&quot; title=&quot;nduck.v104.normal&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/nduck.v104.normal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; height=&quot;92&quot; /&gt;Aiming to be a competitor of Google, so far they are doing a fairly good job. I mean let&#39;s face it, they&#39;ll never be as big as the company but they are fast and show very relevant results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy the fact that they don&#39;t lock you into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dontbubble.us/&quot;&gt;bubble&lt;/a&gt;, which means that you get results based on your search, not based on what you&#39;ve liked, searched for prior or what THEY (Google, Bing, Yahoo) think you want. They also don&#39;t store your results or search history so everything presented is not biased in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My FAVORITE part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; is that they have all these neat short cuts to navigate around and an awesome set of &lt;a href=&quot;http://duckduckgo.com/goodies.html&quot;&gt;goodies&lt;/a&gt; that geeks can use to get better search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, they are a huge win and I hope to see them grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll admit, I still use Google cause sometimes I WANT biased results, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://duckduckgo.com/&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; is becoming something I&#39;m using more and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/life/2012/01/10/duckduckgo-just-works.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/life/2012/01/10/duckduckgo-just-works.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing the Noise Lounge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, now that I&#39;m done ranting about &lt;a title=&quot;Goodbye Go Daddy!&quot; href=&quot;http://timw.co/good-bye-go-daddy/&quot;&gt;Godaddy&lt;/a&gt; and all of the nonsense going on over there, I decided to focus my efforts on something more positive. Over the holiday break (I took a few days off), I decided to put the finishing touch on a website I&#39;d been wanting to launch for some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone  wp-image-245&quot; title=&quot;The Noise Lounge&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;332&quot; height=&quot;66&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months back, I reached out to some friends who share a similar interest in music but were not completely satisfied with the current sites out there. After figuring everything out and getting one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kyleruane.com&quot;&gt;best web designers&lt;/a&gt; alive to help me design a logo, I set to work on the actual meat of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, December 30, I pushed the big publish button and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenoiselounge.com&quot;&gt;The Noise Lounge&lt;/a&gt; went live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look... tell me what you think...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/life/music/2012/01/05/introducing-the-noise-lounge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/life/music/2012/01/05/introducing-the-noise-lounge.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goodbye Go Daddy!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ohhhh man, I can&#39;t even begin to explain how happy I am right now. Let me give you a little back story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite a few years ago when I first started getting into the &quot;web business&quot; I needed a registrar. Back then there wasn&#39;t too many to choose from and everywhere I looked &lt;a href=&quot;http://godaddyboycott.org/&quot;&gt;Go Daddy&lt;/a&gt; stood out as not only being the cheapest but being the biggest and most reliable. Back then, that&#39;s all I cared about. Since then I&#39;ve learned that having a good registrar (as well as a webhost) is just as important as having a good mechanic, lawyer or even doctor. They essentially have control over your domain (even though you own it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I started seeing all the horrible things about &lt;a href=&quot;http://godaddyboycott.org/&quot;&gt;Go Daddy&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;m not a big fan of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/6930045/ns/business/t/ad-godaddy-too-hot-handle/&quot;&gt;advertising&lt;/a&gt;, not only because it is just something I don&#39;t think everyone needs to see (namely children), but they are using sex to sell domain names. It doesn&#39;t&#39; even make sense. Aside from that though, I hate that I pay them a good sum of money each year and they still email and call and try to up-sell me around every corner. I know what I&#39;m doing, I bought what I wanted. It&#39;s like a Walmart employee following me home to try and sell me catnip when I don&#39;t even have a cat. It&#39;s just poor business. Then there was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/03/31/bob-parsons-godaddy-ceo-elephant-hunt_n_843121.html&quot;&gt;incident&lt;/a&gt; involving the owner of the company shooting an elephant for sport. I&#39;m not an animal activist, but I do have respect for the creatures we share the earth with and think the whole thing was just one big publicity stunt. The final thing that pushed me over the edge was &lt;a href=&quot;http://godaddyboycott.org/&quot;&gt;Go Daddy&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s recent show of support in favor of the SOPA bill. I&#39;m not for piracy, but I&#39;m extremely against the SOPA bill and what it stands for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/transferProof.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone  wp-image-236&quot; title=&quot;transferProof&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/transferProof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; height=&quot;210&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been telling my clients for years to stay away from them and finally last night at 1am, I decided to take my own advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by transferring my personal domains and then followed that by all my business domains as well. It was time, and I feel very good about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/life/2011/12/23/good-bye-go-daddy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/life/2011/12/23/good-bye-go-daddy.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Piling up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-227 alignright&quot; title=&quot;projects&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/projects-300x219.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;189&quot; height=&quot;138&quot; /&gt;It&#39;s that time of year again... &lt;a title=&quot;Thankful&quot; href=&quot;http://timw.co/thankful/&quot;&gt;Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; is over, Black Friday and Cyber Monday have passed. It&#39;s now time to look forward to Christmas. Christmas shopping is underway, I finally let my wife to play Christmas music and decorate the house. The one thing that glares at me though, is that just a week beyond Christmas is New Years... and the start of 2012. I&#39;m not big on resolutions or anything of that nature, but I am big on starting fresh and I&#39;ve got a TON of projects sitting around that I&#39;d really like to get done and completed before the end of this year. I know it won&#39;t make a single bit of difference if they are done next week or the last week of January, but to me... having them done before my calendar changes to 2012 makes me feel much better about starting off the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s funny how I got to this point, because a few of these projects are ones that have been hanging around since much earlier this year. They, for some reason, have just continued to get pushed from month to month. Maybe this year for 2012 I should make a resolution to get everything done that year and not wait till December... it&#39;ll never work, but it&#39;s a nice thought right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2011/12/02/piling-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2011/12/02/piling-up.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thankful</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&#39;ve safely made it to Kansas and am going to be spending the next week with most of my immediate family. There are 11 of us in the house plus 4 dogs. It&#39;s going to be a great week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sitting around this afternoon just thinking of how lucky I am. Not be cause of what I have, but because I am part of a big family that truly loves each other. Every year we try to get together for one holiday (Thanksgiving or Christmas) and have a gift exchange. It&#39;s always hard to think of what to ask for because the best part of it is the experience. Spending time with this many people (and animals) under one roof may seem crazy to a lot of people, but it&#39;s exactly where I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone comes from a different family but I encourage you to take a moment and express what you are thankful for this year and if you are blessed enough to come from a family like mine, make sure you thank the members that have made it what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2011/11/23/thankful.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2011/11/23/thankful.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wordpress Post Tags or Categories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-213&quot; title=&quot;tags&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/tags1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;175&quot; /&gt;I&#39;m in active development in a new WordPress theme and came across the age old question. Should I built in support for tags or not? Should I just leave the user with the ability to only use categories? I&#39;m tempted to give them the option, but would I be doing them an injustice since most people rarely use tags and the ones that do, don&#39;t use them right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a huge fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://tentblogger.com/about/&quot;&gt;TentBlogger&lt;/a&gt; and decided to check out his website for an opinion. In his post &quot;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The Reasons I Use Categories Only for My Blogs and Why I Think Tags Are Absolutely Worthless&quot; href=&quot;http://tentblogger.com/tags-categories/&quot; rel=&quot;bookmark&quot;&gt;The Reasons I Use Categories Only for My Blogs and Why I Think Tags Are Absolutely Worthless&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, it helped me come to the conclusion that I&#39;m going to omit tags from this upcoming theme I&#39;m working on. I&#39;m not even going to build it in. I&#39;m not saying that I&#39;ll never build another WordPress theme that has &quot;tag&quot; abilities, but for the time being, and for SEO&#39;s sake... I think we can go with out tags for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2011/11/08/tags-or-categories.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2011/11/08/tags-or-categories.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Free Stuff is Fun</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone loves free stuff... and that&#39;s why myself and the others involved in the application &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hostednotes.com/&quot;&gt;Hosted Notes&lt;/a&gt; have decided to make it free. That&#39;s right.. free. Now go signup and enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hostednotes.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-203 alignnone&quot; title=&quot;logo&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;404&quot; height=&quot;146&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2011/11/08/free-stuff-is-fun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2011/11/08/free-stuff-is-fun.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oldie but a Goodie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an old video I made a over a year ago for fun. Feel free to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/11731234?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=CE4113&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;366&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/random/2011/11/02/oldie-but-a-goodie.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/random/2011/11/02/oldie-but-a-goodie.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Human Mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-185&quot; title=&quot;The Human Mind&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/humanCodeMind-245x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Human Mind&quot; width=&quot;245&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;So yesterday I was thinking it was time to clean up my computer a little bit as I felt it was running a little sluggish. I looked around and finally found a program called &quot;Mac Keeper&quot; and thought I&#39;d give it a try. I should have done my research first as it ended up deleting quite a few of things I needed, such as a ton of program settings. Now I&#39;m sure there&#39;s a setting that would avoid this but either way it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, some how it managed to delete a working folder of a project which was 90% complete. Once I realized this I went into complete shock and began a search for a program that could recover the data. I finally found a program that would get my settings back but that folder was gone for good. I put my head down and realized I&#39;d have to start all over from scratch and knew I had better quit sulking and just get to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny thing though, I was able to re-create the ENTIRE project in less than 30 minutes compared to the hours it took to get there prior. Why was this? I guess the human mind just works in amazing ways. I felt like Shawn Spencer on Psych... as I created new files with the same name, the code just came back to me... and flowed out of my fingertips to the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lucky day I guess...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/life/2011/10/27/the-human-mind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/life/2011/10/27/the-human-mind.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Addition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/ernieBallvpJr.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-157 alignright&quot; title=&quot;Ernie Ball VP Jr&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/ernieBallvpJr-300x204.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ernie Ball VP Jr&quot; width=&quot;270&quot; height=&quot;184&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it&#39;s been a bit since I&#39;ve added anything to my pedal board (which I will review at some point), but I was recently given a gift from a client. It&#39;s an Ernie Ball Volume Pedal JR. I&#39;ve never used a VP before but have always been interested in getting one. The pedal came in the mail yesterday as a thank you for a recent site I built (which we&#39;ll keep nameless at this point) and I&#39;ve only gotten to play with it a little bit last night. My main guitar and pedal board are still up at the church from playing this last weekend, so I had to use one of my older guitars to play with it. So far I&#39;ve very impressed with the quality of it. I also like that it has a switch that changes the swell for two unique sounds. Personally I like one over the other so I&#39;ll probably not be changing that. I have band practice tonight at church and hope to give this a good run and see how it sounds on stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say that this was an awesome gift from a client. They actually asked my project manager (who knows me pretty well) what I was interested in and he gave them this suggestion. I can&#39;t express how grateful and how excited I am to add this to my collection!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/music/2011/10/19/new-addition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/music/2011/10/19/new-addition.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Site vs App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When working on proposals for new work, I often get a raised eyebrow when someone hears that a simple app can cost a lot more than a large website. They think because the app might only consist of a single page and the site hundreds that the site is somehow much harder to put together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When pondering this, I came up with an analogy... condos vs cottages. A condo can house many families while a cottage is generally for a single small family. If this is true, then why is it sometimes it can cost more to have a cottage built vs having a string of condo&#39;s built. The answer is simple... customization my friend, customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An online/web app may be smaller in size than a large website but believe me it usually takes a lot longer to build one out, and I can almost all but guarantee that the final product will have much more custom work in it than your standard website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, that this is not ALWAYS the case, but in my line of work more times than not this rings true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2011/10/18/site-vs-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2011/10/18/site-vs-app.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>iOS 5 - My Thoughts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I updated to iOS 5.0 just a couple days ago and so far so good. It&#39;s hard to believe that an OS update of any kind can show considerable improvement in speed when the device hasn&#39;t changed at all... as I&#39;m still running the iPhone 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m very impressed with the updates to the notifications and the camera as a whole but to me the one thing that I love the most is the text-expansion. I&#39;ll admit it, I&#39;m not very good at texting and having the ability to create my own shortcuts makes for a much easier time to respond to the few texts I get on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite so far is &quot;amw&quot;... when I type that it will expand to &quot;let me ask my wife&quot;. This gets me out of a lot of things I don&#39;t want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2011/10/15/ios-5-my-thoughts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2011/10/15/ios-5-my-thoughts.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Back from Vacation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just got back from vacation and it was wonderful. I absolutely love what I do, but even those of us who have our &quot;dream jobs&quot; need a vacation from it every once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/la-sunset1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-104 alignleft&quot; title=&quot;Lake Anna Sunset&quot; src=&quot;http://timw.co/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/la-sunset1-300x191.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;210&quot; height=&quot;134&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I were able to spend the last week at a cabin on Lake Anna in the middle of Virginia. We planned our trip perfectly so there was very few people on the lake while we were there. We spent our days kayaking around the lake and swimming just off shore near our cabin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the last night there we laid out on the dock and just talked about the things in our lives we loved, the things we hated and the things we wanted to improve upon. I feel as though this was a huge highlight of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2011/09/03/back-from-vacation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2011/09/03/back-from-vacation.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Purple Door - Mobile App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So getting ready to leave for Purple Door Festival 2011 tomorrow and in the meantime I thought I&#39;d throw together a quick mobile app using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jquerymobile.com/&quot;&gt;jQuery Mobile&lt;/a&gt; so I&#39;d have a better way of keeping the schedule in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested can find it here - &lt;a href=&quot;http://timw.co/pd/&quot;&gt;Purple Door Mobile Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/mobile/music/2011/08/11/purple-door-mobile-app.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/mobile/music/2011/08/11/purple-door-mobile-app.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>30 Hour Fast 2011</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I consider myself luck that over the past 3 years I&#39;ve been able to be a part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parkerhill.org/&quot;&gt;Parker Hill&lt;/a&gt; and their student ministries department. Over this last weekend I was able to take part in what is called the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parkerhill.org/youthportal/?page_id=13&quot;&gt;30 hour fast&lt;/a&gt;. Basically all of the students from middle school to high school raise money and awareness by giving up their right to eat for 30 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a clip of the highlight video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/20488861?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/life/2011/02/28/30-hour-fast-2011.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/life/2011/02/28/30-hour-fast-2011.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hosted Notes Launch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I should probably be more worried about what I&#39;m going to get my &lt;a href=&quot;http://stephwhitacre.com/&quot;&gt;wife&lt;/a&gt; today, but I also wanted to take time out to announce the launch of the first ever online web app that I was able to be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://hostednotes.com&quot;&gt;Hosted Notes&lt;/a&gt; and it&#39;s tool to help keep track of passwords. It was originally concieved with freelances in mind. When doing a website for a client, you usually end up with many different passwords and programs you need access to. With Hosted Notes you can keep track of all of them in one simple secure place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe we&#39;ll be launching more features over time, but feel free to check it out ant let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2011/02/14/hosted-notes-launch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2011/02/14/hosted-notes-launch.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Argyll Studios Re-Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After many months of working on this site, we&#39;re finally ready to make our launch public to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presenting the redesign of my company - &lt;a href=&quot;http://argyllstudios.com&quot;&gt;Argyll Studios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://timw.co/development/2010/12/02/argyll-studios-re-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://timw.co/development/2010/12/02/argyll-studios-re-design.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>